Personal Papers of Lester Nurick
World Bank Group Archives
Personal Papers of Lester Nurick
1946 - 2004
WB IBRD/IDA NURICK
24.07 linear feet of textual records; 8 photographs
World Bank Group Archives
Nurick, Lester
Lester Nurick was born in New York City on December 2, 1914. He graduated from City College of New York in 1934 and later Brooklyn Law School in 1937. After graduation, Nurick practiced law at the firm of Evans, Rees, and Orr in New York City from 1938 to 1941. In 1941, Nurick moved to Washington D.C., and served in the position of Senior Attorney for the Public Utilities Division of the U.S. Government Securities and Exchange Commission from 1941 to 1943.
In 1943, Nurick was drafted into the United States Army tank corps. He later joined the Judge Advocate General's Department Officer Candidate School (JAG OCS), and eventually served as the Chief of the International Law Branch from 1943 to 1946.
In 1946, Nurick joined the legal department of the World Bank. He first served as Counsel from 1946 to 1968, and later as the Associate General Counsel from 1968 to 1979. From 1979 to 1980, he took over the roles of Vice President and General Counsel. In his time at the World Bank, Nurick helped establish the International Finance Corporation (IFC) in 1956, the International Development Association (IDA) in 1960, and the International Centre for Settlement of Investment Disputes (ICSID) in 1966. He specialized in the questions of privileges and immunities of international organizations, taxation and finance (Bond issuances), and staff compensation issues. Nurick retired from the World Bank in 1980, but continued to work as a legal consultant afterwards.
After retiring from the World Bank, Nurick became a partner at the law firm Wilmer, Cutler, and Pickering. He also taught international law courses at George Washington University Law School, and served as guest lecturer at various law schools and universities.
Nurick passed away on 9 October 2014 in Potomac, Maryland.
Published
The topics to which the records relate reflect issues of personal interest to Nurick or issues which he handled on behalf of his clients. Records relate to the legal structure of the World Bank as an institution and of its lending operations. Records relate to litigation and specific World Bank lending projects, such as the Volta River power projects in Ghana, the Shashe project in Botswana, the Falconbridge ferronickel project in the Dominican Republic, and the Boke project in Guinea. Records also relate to administrative and personnel issues in the World Bank. A small amount of materials collected, such as publications and invitations, that relate to Nurick's time at the World Bank Group are also included.
This material was accumulated by Lester Nurick during his tenure at the World Bank. He took the files with him when he retired, and subsequently donated them to the World Bank Group Archives in the form of three separate accruals.
Accruals are not expected.
* See Records of the Office of the General Counsel ([WB IBRD/IDA LEG ](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/records-of-office-of-general-counsel)).
* See oral history interview of [Lester Nurick](http://oralhistory.worldbank.org/person/nurick-lester).
Records are subject to conditions in the donor's instrument of gift and to the World Bank Policy on Access to Information.
- Subject files, 1947 - 1996; WB IBRD/IDA NURICK-5864S; 17.86 linear feet of textual record; 7 photographs
  Published
  The files consist of correspondence, reports, legal memoranda, briefs, and printed items. The topics to which the records relate reflect issues of personal interest to Nurick or issues that he handled on behalf of his clients. Records relate to the World Bank as an institution, such as the Bank's Articles of Agreement, the Bretton Woods Agreement, sovereign immunity, the International Finance Corporation, immunities and powers of the Bank, and Bank membership issues involving China, the Palestine Liberation Organization, and Iran. Also included are records relating to bond issues and finance, taxation, co-financing, and securities and investment. Some records relate to litigation, such as a Federal Communications Commission case and a case involving university tuition payments. Files on specific World Bank lending projects include records related to the [Volta River power projects](http://www.worldbank.org/projects/P000834/volta-power-project?lang=en) in Ghana (including photographs), the Shashe projects in Botswana ([Shashe Engineering Project](http://www.worldbank.org/projects/P000126/shashe-engineering-project?lang=en) and [Shashe Construction and Supplementary Loan Project](http://www.worldbank.org/projects/P000127/shashe-construction-supplementary-loan-project?lang=en)), the [Falconbridge ferronickel project](http://www.worldbank.org/projects/P006977/nickel-project-falconbridge?lang=en) in the Dominican Republic, and the [Boke UNDP Technical Assistance project](http://www.worldbank.org/projects/P001019/boke-extension-undp-technical-assistance-project?lang=en) in Guinea. Records also relate to personnel issues, such as staff rights and obligations, garnishment, and staff compensation.
  Records are arranged alphabetically by topic.
  Accruals are not expected.
  * See Central Files - Membership files ([WB IBRD/IDA ADMCF-05](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/membership-files)) for records related to World Bank Group member relations and membership issues.
  * See Central Files - Borrowing and bond issues ([WB IBRD IDA ADMCF-09](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/borrowing-and-bond-issues)) for records regarding the Bank Group's borrowing operations and issuing of bonds.
  * See Central Files - Finance files ([WB IBRD IDA ADMCF-10](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/finance-files)) for records related to the development of World Bank Group policy and financial management.
  * See Records of the Industry and Mining Sector - Liaison, partnerships and program collaboration ([WB IBRD/IDA IND-01](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/liaison-partnerships-and-program-collaboration-2)) for records related to the United Nations Revolving Fund for Natural Resources Exploration.
  Records are subject to conditions in the donor's instrument of gift and to the World Bank Policy on Access to Information.
  - Sixth Annual Meeting - Telephone directory of Board of Governors, 1951-01-01 - 1951-12-31; 30297704
  - Legal proceedings - Docket No. 9362 - IBRD vs All America Cables and Radio, Inc. - Brief for the complainants, 1951-01-01 - 1951-12-31; 30297706
  - Ghana - Volta River Project - Ghanaian Times article - January 22, 1962, 1962-01-22; 30297702
  - Ghana - Volta River Project - Valco agreements initiated with Ghana, Nov 17, 1960, and parliamentary debates, 1960-01-01 - 1961-12-31; 30297687
  - Ghana - Volta River Project - Kaiser memoranda, 1961-01-01 - 1965-12-31; 30297686
  - Ghana - Volta Project - Administrative Memoranada - Appointments, 1961-01-01 - 1967-12-31; 30297676
  - Ghana - Volta Project - Amendments and Agreements, 1962-01-01 - 1966-12-31; 30297675
  - Ghana - Volta Project - Project file - Volume 3, 1962-01-01 - 1962-12-31; 30297681
  - Ghana - Volta Project - Project file - Volume 2, 1962-01-01 - 1962-12-31; 30297680
  - Ghana - Volta Project - Project file - Volume 1, 1960-01-01 - 1964-12-31; 30297679
  - Ghana - Volta Project I - IBRD Agreement, 1961-01-01 - 1962-12-31; 30297678
  - Legal Memoranada of Lester Nurick, 1986-01-01 - 1991-12-31; 30297677
  - Yugoslavia - correspondence re: 'The Black Mountains', 1955-07-13 - 1955-07-14; 30297717
  - Ghana - Volta River Project - Volta and Ghana documents, 1959-01-01 - 1967-12-31; 30297685
  - Staff Compensation - Masiello vs. UN - 1979, 1979-01-01 - 1979-12-31; 01850815
  - Miscellaneous Funds - Shah's proposal, Venezuela Fund, OPEC Special Fund - 1974 to 1976, 1974-01-01 - 1976-12-31; 01850816
  - Chilean Nationalization - Act of State Doctrine, Sovereign Immunity - 1971 to 1973, 1971-01-01 - 1973-12-31; 01850817
  - United Nations Revolving Fund for Natural Resources Exploration - 1973 to 1981, 1973-01-01 - 1981-12-31; 01850818
  - Delaume - Material on conflicts and forum - 1974, 1974-01-01 - 1974-12-31; 01850819
  - Volta Power Project, 1961-01-01 - 1967-12-31; 01850820
  - IBRD Agreements - Arbitration, force majeure, security, de facto governments - 1963 to 1970, 1963-01-01 - 1970-12-31; 01850939
  - Exploration and Development Agreement between Bristol Bay Native Corporation and Phillips Petroleum Co. - 1974-1975, 1974-01-01 - 1975-12-31; 01850940
  - IFC Memoranda - Taxes - 1955 to 1957, 1955-01-01 - 1957-12-31; 01850942
  - Tunisia Conciliation - 1968, 1968-01-01 - 1968-12-31; 01850943
  - Taxes - 1951 to 1957, 1951-01-01 - 1957-12-31; 01850944
  - US Bond Issues - Taxes - 1964 to 1975, 1964-01-01 - 1975-12-31; 01850945
  - Japan - Nurick recollection of dealing with lawyers from Japan - 1990, 1990-01-01 - 1990-12-31; 01850946
  - Private Co-Financing Arrangements - Inter-American Development Bank, 1977-01-01 - 1977-12-31; 30045168
  - US - IMF quota increase - 1980, 1980-01-01 - 1980-12-31; 01851052
  - Miscellaneous - International law memoranda and references - 1950 to 1952, 1950-01-01 - 1952-12-31; 01851053
  - General legal memoranda - 1951 to 1968, 1951-01-01 - 1968-12-31; 01851054
  - Federal Communications Commission Case - Hearings before Mr. Resnick, initial decision on basic issues, main briefs - February 1951, 1951-01-01 - 1951-12-31; 01851055
  - Federal Communications Commission Case - Arguments, transcript, decision - February 1953, 1953-01-01 - 1953-12-31; 01851056
  - Federal Communications Commission Case - Paris Telegraph regulations, International Telecommunication Union (ITU), Atlantic City Conference and other international agreements -1949 to 1950, 1949-01-01 - 1950-12-31; 01851057
  - Federal Communications Commission Case - General legal memoranda, Book 2 - 1949-1950, 1949-01-01 - 1950-12-31; 01851058
  - Federal Communications Commission Case - General legal memoranda, Book 4 - 1951 to 1952, 1951-01-01 - 1952-12-31; 01851059
  - Federal Communications Commission Case - Initial decision, briefs and exceptions - 1949 to 1952, 1949-01-01 - 1952-12-31; 01851079
  - Immunities and Powers of the Bank and its members, Articles of Agreement - Volume 1 - 1947 to 1952, 1947-01-01 - 1952-12-31; 01851080
  - Immunities and Powers of the Bank and its members, Articles of Agreement - Volume 2 - 1953 to 1974, 1953-01-01 - 1974-12-31; 01851081
  - Mexican loan - Commission Project 0012 and Mexlight Project 0013 - 1949 to 1951, 1949-01-01 - 1951-12-31; 01851082
  - Botswana - Shashe Project Registration Statement - 1972, 1972-01-01 - 1972-12-31; 01851121
  - Arab boycott - 1979 to 1984, 1979-01-01 - 1984-12-31; 01851122
  - IBRD Energy memoranda - 1978 to 1982, 1978-01-01 - 1982-12-31; 01851123
  - Development Committee Task Force on Multilateral Development Banks - Governance - IBRD and other multilateral development banks - 1991 to 1995, 1991-01-01 - 1995-12-31; 01851124
  - Development Committee Task Force on Multilateral Development Banks - Charters, Guarantees, Political Umbrella - 1995, 1995-01-01 - 1995-12-31; 01851125
  - Staff Compensation - legal memoranda, other organizations, general - 1979 to 1980, 1979-01-01 - 1980-12-31; 01851253
  - Taxes - Miscellaneous - 1975, 1975-01-01 - 1975-12-31; 01851254
  - US Tax, Foreign Source Income, Effect on Bank - 1973, 1973-01-01 - 1973-12-31; 01851255
  - Briefing Book - Review by Administrative Tribunals of the decisions of Governing Bodies - 1954 to 1979, 1954-01-01 - 1979-12-31; 01851256
  - De Facto governments - 1964 to 1965, 1964-01-01 - 1965-12-31; 01851257
  - Lutcher S.A. Celulose e Papel versus Inter-American Development Bank - 1974 to 1976, 1974-01-01 - 1976-12-31; 01851258
  - Tuition Case - Toll versus Moreno - 1981, 1981-01-01 - 1981-12-31; 01851259
  - Broadbent versus Organization of American States Volume 1 - 1979, 1979-01-01 - 1979-12-31; 01851263
  - Broadbent versus Organization of American States Volume 2 - 1979, 1979-01-01 - 1979-12-31; 01851264
  - Broadbent versus Organization of American States Volume 1 - 1977 to 1978, 1977-01-01 - 1978-12-31; 01851265
  - Broadbent Case - Organization of American States briefs - 1978 to 1980, 1978-01-01 - 1980-12-31; 01851266
  - Broadbent versus Organization of American States - Court Appeals - 1978 to 1980, 1978-01-01 - 1980-12-31; 01851267
  - China - Membership - 1980, 1980-01-01 - 1980-12-31; 01851268
  - Iran - Blocking of Assets, World Bank deposits - 1975 to 1980, 1975-01-01 - 1980-12-31; 01851269
  - IFC - Testimony before Congress on Securities Exchange Commission (SEC) exemption legislation - 1990, 1990-01-01 - 1990-12-31; 01851270
  - Privileges and Immunities of IBRD and staff cases, memoranda - 1977 to 1978, 1977-01-01 - 1978-12-31; 01851271
  - Bretton Woods Agreement Act - Securties Act of 1993 [reference materials], 1993-01-01 - 1993-12-31; 01851272
  - Development Committee Task Force on Multilateral Development Banks - Report - 1996, 1996-01-01 - 1996-12-31; 01851273
  - Development Committee Task Force on Multilateral Development Banks - Administrative arrangememts - 1995 to 1996, 1995-01-01 - 1996-12-31; 01851274
  - Bretton Woods Agreement Act Amendments, 1976-01-01 - 1976-12-31; 01851275
  - World Bank Airport Tax - background memoranda re: immunity - 1971, 1971-01-01 - 1971-12-31; 01851276
  - Garnishment - Guinea Paris - 1968 to 1970, 1968-01-01 - 1970-12-31; 01851277
  - Valuation of the Bank's capital - internal memoranda - 1974 to 1981, 1974-01-01 - 1981-12-31; 01851278
  - Valuation of the Bank's capital - US, Asian Development Bank, Inter-American Development Bank - 1977 to 1978, 1977-01-01 - 1978-12-31; 01851279
  - Federal Communications Commission Case - Brief for the complaints - Docket 9362 Volume 2 - 1951, 1951-01-01 - 1951-12-31; 01851280
  - Negative pledge - 1993 to 1994, 1993-01-01 - 1994-12-31; 01851281
  - Human Rights - Inter-American and Regional, legal articles - 1985 to 1988, 1985-01-01 - 1988-12-31; 01851282
  - The Volta River Project - Volume 1 - 1962, 1962-01-01 - 1962-12-31; 01851304
  - The Volta River Project - Volume 2 - 1962, 1962-01-01 - 1962-12-31; 01851305
  - The Volta River Project - 1969, 1969-01-01 - 1969-12-31; 01851320
  - Valco Fifth Potline Expansion - 1975, 1975-01-01 - 1975-12-31; 01851321
  - Shashe Project Legislation - Volume 3 - 1959 to 1972, 1959-01-01 - 1972-12-31; 01851334
  - Shashe Project Company Agreements - Volume 2 - 1959 to 1972, 1959-01-01 - 1972-12-31; 01851335
  - China - 1950 to 1979 - Correspondence - Lester Nurick, 1950-10-11 - 1979-01-24; 01850539
  - Arab Boycott - Laws, Shipping - 1979 to 1984 - Correspondence - Lester Nurick, 1975-05-19 - 1976-05-04; 01850540
  - Peoples Republic of China [PRC] - 1980 - Correspondence - Lester Nurick, 1980-03-24 - 1980-06-17; 01850541
  - Guinea - Boke Project - General Expropriation - 1965 to 1969 - Correspondence - Lester Nurick, 1965-03-16 - 1969-02-13; 01850542
  - Guinea - Boke - Economic Reports and Letters - 1965 to 1966 - Lester Nurick, 1965-12-03 - 1966-03-15; 01850543
  - Legal Memoranda - Articles of Agreement and Powers of the Bank - 1947 to 1974 - Lester Nurick, 1947-06-10 - 1974-01-10; 01850544
  - United States Taxes - Bank Bonds - 1977 - Lester Nurick, 1977-06-01 - 1977-09-15; 01850545
  - Co-financing Arrangements - Arab Boycott - Communications to the United States, Executive Directors and Congress - Lester Nurick, 1975-10-13 - 1977-01-04; 30045054
  - Private Co-Financing Arrangements I - Legal Matters, Lead Banks, and Information - Lester Nurick, 1977-01-22 - 1977-08-31; 30045171
  - Joint Financing - Correspondence - Lester Nurick, 1969-02-03 - 1972-07-25; 30045172
  - Dominican Republic - Falconbridge Ferronickel Project - Volume 1, 1969-01-01 - 1970-12-31; 01850749
  - Dominican Republic - Falconbridge Ferronickel Project - Volume 2, 1969-01-01 - 1970-12-31; 30045058
  - Interest Equalization Tax (US) - 1963-1965, 1963-07-18 - 1966-06-10; 01850571
  - Shashe Project - Botswana - Volume 1. 1971, 1971-01-01 - 1971-12-31; 01850572
  - Shashe Project - Botswana - World Bank Documents, 1971-01-01 - 1971-12-31; 30045069
  - Special Projects - UN Special Fund, Bank Memoranda - 1966-1968, 1966-01-01 - 1968-12-31; 01850591
  - United Nations Revolving Fund for Natural Resources Exploitation -1976-1981, 1976-01-01 - 1981-12-31; 01850592
  - Acquired Rights of International Civil Servants (Reference Material) - Volume 1 - 1978, 1978-01-01 - 1978-12-31; 01850593
  - Acquired Rights of International Civil Servants (Reference Material) - Volume 2 - 1978, 1978-01-01 - 1978-12-31; 01850594
  - Herbert Harvey Inc. vs. National Labor Relations Board - 1966-1973, 1966-01-01 - 1973-12-31; 01850595
  - Handbook on the Legal Status, Privileges and Immunities of the United Nations - 1952, 1952-01-01 - 1952-12-31; 01850625
  - Strikes, work stoppages - International Organizations - 1976 to 1979, 1976-01-01 - 1979-12-31; 01850626
  - Administrative Appeals - January 1977 to April 1979, 1977-01-01 - 1979-04-30; 01850627
  - Human Rights - US Specific Laws (Reference Material) - 1967 to 1979, 1967-01-01 - 1979-12-31; 01850628
  - Human Rights - Basic Documents (Reference Material) - 1948 to 1969, 1948-01-01 - 1969-12-31; 01850629
  - Miscellaneous security arrangements - 1952 to 1960, 1952-01-01 - 1960-12-31; 01850630
  - Sovereign Immunity - 1978, 1978-01-01 - 1978-12-31; 01850631
  - Palestine Liberation Organization (PLO) - 1979 to 1980, 1979-01-01 - 1980-12-31; 01850765
  - Development Projects - published articles: VALCO VoltaDam, Kaiser Projects Projects in Indonesia, Falconbridge, Kaiser-Jamaica Bauxitenegotiations, 1980-01-01 - 1984-12-31; 01850766
  - American Society of International Law (ASIL) - Bellagio Meeting papers, 1967, 1967-01-01 - 1967-12-31; 01850767
  - Staff Compensation - Legal Opinions (Bank and Outside Counsel) - 1979, 1979-01-01 - 1979-12-31; 01850768
  - Tied funds - US Legislation, miscellaneous memoranda, Vietnam, Iran, Executive Directors' actions - 1977 to 1979, 1977-01-01 - 1979-12-31; 01850769
  - Voting in Bank, IMF - 1980, 1980-01-01 - 1980-12-31; 01850770
  - World Bank Administrative Tribunal Cases - Staff Compensation Cases - Brief of the World Bank - 1981, 1981-01-01 - 1981-12-31; 01850771
  - Novak vs. World Bank - Volume 2 - 1979 to 1980, 1979-01-01 - 1980-12-31; 01850772
  - US Loyalty Program - 1953 to 1986, 1953-01-01 - 1986-12-31; 01850773
  - Preliminary IFC Memoranda - January to October 1955, 1955-01-01 - 1955-12-31; 01850778
  - IFC memoranda - Legal, etcetera - 1954 to 1960, 1954-01-01 - 1960-12-31; 01850779
  - US Legislation - Gold Bill - 1972, 1972-01-01 - 1972-12-31; 01850780
  - US Bond issues Volume 1 - 1964 to 1975, 1964-01-01 - 1975-12-31; 01850781
  - Negative pledge and security arrangements Volume 1 - 1954 to 1976, 1954-01-01 - 1976-12-31; 01850782
  - Bretton Woods Agreements Act and World Bank amendments (includes Bitterman's History of Negotiations) - 1948 to 1971, 1948-01-01 - 1971-12-31; 01850783
  - Private Co-Financing Arrangements II - Legal matters, lead banks, information, 1977-01-01 - 1981-12-31; 30045170
  - IBRD - Bond Issues - Miscellaneous - 1980 to 1983, 1980-01-01 - 1983-12-31; 01850799
  - Opinions of General Counsel and other opinions - 1964 to 1977, 1964-01-01 - 1977-12-31; 01850800
  - Conference on Bank staff rights and obligations - Internal documents - 1969 to 1978, 1969-01-01 - 1978-12-31; 01850801
  - Securities and investment memoranda Volume 1 - 1947 to 1956, 1947-01-01 - 1956-12-31; 01850802
  - IBRD - Negative pledge experience (Delaume) - 1961, 1961-01-01 - 1961-12-31; 01850803
  - Private Co-Financing Arrangements - IBRD contracts, private loan contracts, 1975-01-01 - 1977-12-31; 30045169
  - American Society of International Law (ASIL) - Bellagio Meeting background papers - August 1967, 1967-01-01 - 1967-12-31; 01850813
  - Expropriation study - 1972, 1972-01-01 - 1972-12-31; 01850814
  - Chenery, Arab boycott, Conflict of Interest - Published articles and memoranda - 1975 - Lester Nurick, 1975-01-01 - 1975-12-31; 01850941
- Chronological correspondence, 1946 - 2004; WB IBRD/IDA NURICK-01; 5.81 linear feet of textual records
  The files primarily consist of correspondence to and from Nurick, and drafts of correspondence, reports and other records. The chronological files kept by Nurick capture a variety of topics, related both to Bank work and to personal activities. As the correspondence was captured chronologically, each folder contains records relating to a large variety of (and sometimes unrelated) topics, activities or events. Researchers looking for records related to specific topics, activities or events may need to review all records within the Series using dates as a guideline. The correspondence relates, but is not limited, to: member contributions; membership (including origin of Part 1 and Part 2 countries); Bank subscription increases; bond issues; borrowing and loans to various countries; co-financing; IDA replenishments; Bank financial statements; valuation of capital; arrears and settlement of foreign claims; International Finance Corporation matters; Loan Committee; Development Committee; Joint Ministerial Committee; Bank IDA Statutory Committees; Disbursement Committee; selection of Robert McNamara; the Arab boycott; administrative and other personnel matters, including litigation, Administrative Tribunal and appeals; procurement guidelines; relations with other organizations and the US government; Second Committee of the UN; EEC Special Action Programme; and many others.
  Records are arranged chronologically.
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence - Volume 2, 1962-01-01 - 2004-12-31; 30045016
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence - Volume 1, 1963-01-01 - 1980-07-31; 30045015
  - Chronological File - 1980, 1980-01-01 - 1980-12-31; 30045014
  - Chronological File - 1979, 1979-01-01 - 1979-12-31; 30045013
  - Chronological File - 1978, 1978-01-01 - 1978-12-31; 30045012
  - Chronological File - 1977, 1977-01-01 - 1977-12-31; 30045011
  - Chronological File - 1976, 1976-01-01 - 1976-12-31; 30045010
  - Chronological File - 1975, 1975-01-01 - 1975-12-31; 30045009
  - Chronological File - 1974, 1974-01-01 - 1974-12-31; 30045008
  - Chronological File - 1973, 1973-01-01 - 1973-12-31; 30045007
  - Chronological File - 1972, 1972-01-01 - 1972-12-31; 30045006
  - Chronological File - 1971, 1971-01-01 - 1971-12-31; 30045005
  - Chronological File - 1970, 1970-01-01 - 1970-12-31; 30045004
  - Chronological File - 1969, 1969-01-01 - 1969-12-31; 30045003
  - Chronological File - July 1968 to December 1968, 1968-07-01 - 1968-12-31; 30045002
  - International Bank for Reconstruction and Development (IBRD) Chronological File - January 1964 to December 1964, 1964-01-01 - 1964-12-31; 30045001
  - Chronological File - January 1968 to December 1968, 1968-01-01 - 1968-12-31; 30045000
  - International Bank for Reconstruction and Development (IBRD) Chronological File - January 1967 to December 1967, 1967-01-01 - 1967-12-31; 30044999
  - International Bank for Reconstruction and Development (IBRD) Chronological File - January 1966 to December 1966, 1966-01-01 - 1966-12-31; 30044998
  - International Bank for Reconstruction and Development (IBRD) Chronological File - January 1965 to December 1965, 1965-01-01 - 1965-12-31; 30044997
  - Chronological File (job applicants) - February 1964 to September 1965, 1964-02-01 - 1965-09-30; 30044996
  - International Bank for Reconstruction and Development (IBRD) Chronological File - January 1963 to December 1963, 1963-01-01 - 1963-12-31; 30044992
  - International Bank for Reconstruction and Development (IBRD) Chronological File - January 1962 to December 1962, 1962-01-01 - 1962-12-31; 30044991